<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Linux - Tag - Malware Hell</title><link>https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Linux - Tag - Malware Hell</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>c3rb3r3u5d3d53c@gmail.com (c3rb3r3u5d3d53c)</managingEditor><webMaster>c3rb3r3u5d3d53c@gmail.com (c3rb3r3u5d3d53c)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/tags/linux/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fish as a User Shell in Linux</title><link>https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/2023/02/fish-user-shell.en.md/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>c3rb3ru5d3d53c</author><guid>https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/2023/02/fish-user-shell.en.md/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/9c1dde5dfce4c0b161452996e00692e8bad35dbccc23f3a98fcf9d4d1efcef66.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction The purpose of this article is to provide reasoning behind why I&rsquo;m a fish shell user and how to I setup fish ðŸŸ shell on all my Linux machines. Before we begin, we need to understand what fish shell is.
Fish is a Unix shell with a focus on interactivity and usability. Fish is designed to give the user features by default, rather than by configuration. Fish is considered an exotic shell since it does not rigorously adhere to POSIX shell standards, at the discretion of the maintainers.]]></description></item><item><title>Hooking C Runtime or libc</title><link>https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/2023/02/hooking-libc.en.md/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>c3rb3ru5d3d53c</author><guid>https://c3rb3r3u5d3d53c.github.io/2023/02/hooking-libc.en.md/</guid><description>Introduction A friend at work asked me if we can actively change argc when executing a target program without modifying the target program. I was not sure at the time what the solution would be. However, after some thought; I thought about LD_PRELOAD and using it to hook specific functions. I figured, well it probably won&amp;rsquo;t allow the hooking of libc, but in reality it does. This is of course interesting behavior that can be leveraged for offensive and defensive security research practices.</description></item></channel></rss>