<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documents on Malware Hell</title><link>https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documents on Malware Hell</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/c3rb3ru5d3d53c">c3rb3ru5d3d53c&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KVM Malware Lab Guide</title><link>https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/kvm-malware-lab/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/kvm-malware-lab/</guid><description>Malware Lab with KVM This is my guide for setting up your very own malware lab using KVM.
Before you start, this guide assumes you have an AirVPN subscription or another equivelent one, which provides a .ovpn file.
NOTE: I like to have internet enabled on my analysis VMs and this comes with extra security considerations and potential risk if you do not perform the setup correcty. This guide is not intended for beginners.
If you have used VirtualBox or VMWare Workstation in the past, Spice is just like the guest tools for these but for KVM, which allows you to copy/paste and copy samples to your VMs from your host machine.</description></item><item><title>Malware Analysis Tool List</title><link>https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/malware-analysis-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://c3rb3ru5d3d53c.github.io/docs/malware-analysis-tools/</guid><description>Malware Analysis Tools This document contains an extensive list of the malware analysis tools I use on a regular basis. 😄
tool description x64dbg Debugger Ghidra Reverse Engineering DNSpy Reverse Engineering windbg Debugging Python Scripting OWASP Zap Web Debugging HxD Hex Editing HashMyFiles File Hashing VSCodium Coding PEStudio Triage IDR Interactive Delphi Reconstructor PEBear PE Editing and Triage pe-seive Malware Unpacking Detect it Easy Triage TOR Dark Web Browsing Cutter Reverse Engineering VB Decompiler Pro Reverse Engineering VB Samples Resource Hacker Triage and Unpacking dControl Disabling Windows Defender scDbg Shellcode Emulation xlmDeobfuscator Deobfuscation of XLM Maldocs oletools Maldoc Analysis Sysinternals Dynamic Analysis Nauz File Detector Triage PDF Stream Dumper PDF Maldoc Analysis Wireshark Network Analysis MalUnpack Unpacking Malware Orca MSI Editor 7zip Extracting Archives Dependency Walker DLL Analysis de4dot .</description></item></channel></rss>